Hello everyone, today I would like to introduce you to Clo 7.3, a new feature designed in the updated version 30 days later.
There are seven modules in total, which are the main functions, 2D, 3D, virtual model, color, rendering, and mode.
First of all, let's talk about the main function, Everywhere.
From the beginning, the Everywhere function can be easily optimized in Clo for various digital spaces, such as games, the round universe, and entertainment spaces.
The Everywhere function is currently in the testing stage, and all users who pre-register on the Connect web page can use it.
Pre-register can be done on the Connect web page Everywhere option and unlimited open.
Please note that Everywhere is a test function.
The policy of use may change in the future.
In this example, we will guide you to use Everywhere to complete the process of testing clothes, network optimization, binding skeleton, UV fill and baking pattern.
In the software interface, click on the icon in the upper right corner to open Everywhere.
The Everywhere window appears in the upper right corner of the 2D version of the test window.
The number of multidirectional network spaces for clothes and virtual models is displayed in the lower left corner of the 3D window.
The Everywhere window is divided into two options, clothes and materials.
In the clothes option, you can optimize the multidirectional network space and bind the skeleton.
In the material option, you can perform operations such as UV filling, baking pattern, and material application.
First, let's take a look at the multidirectional network optimization in the clothing option.
Multidirectional refers to the network that constitutes the clothing.
When you share your creations on different platforms, the number and capacity of the support network may be different.
Therefore, considering the different functions of each platform, you can use the multidirectional network optimization function to maintain the 3D clothing form.
At the same time, the optimization of the multidirectional network number is effective.
Before the optimization process is carried out, you can check the total network space of the current clothing.
In the Everywhere window, the number on the right side of the clothing indicates the current network space of the clothing.
This number includes the number of buttons or accessories on the clothing.
In addition, in the next virtual model column, you can check the multidirectional network space of the virtual model.
In addition, in the lower left corner of the 3D window, you can verify the number of multidirectional network spaces.
Here you can check the number of multidirectional network spaces for the version and the accessory.
How to optimize the multidirectional network.
First, in the clothing option in the multidirectional network optimization, enter the required multidirectional network number in the blank box on the left.
Then click optimize.
Apply the customized multidirectional network to the specified number.
If the accessory or button is a high-quality model, it can be done individually.
Then click OK.
You can optimize the individual optimization.
For the individual optimization of the accessory, you need to select the button or accessory to be used in the material window.
After selecting, enter the required value into the technology box in the multidirectional network optimization in the multidirectional network optimization at the bottom of the attribute editor window.
This will optimize the multidirectional network of the accessory to be matched to the specified number.
Next, I will explain the option of binding the skeleton.
First, the binding skeleton is in the 3D virtual model.
It is a process of creating a similar skeleton structure so that it can be linked and moved.
In the binding skeleton function of Everywhere, the binding skeleton can promote the synchronization of the created clothing and virtual model.
This design will connect the skeleton joints of the created virtual model with the clothing, ensuring that the movement of the clothing and virtual model are synchronized.
The binding skeleton of Everywhere is specifically suitable for the human virtual model with joints.
And when the virtual model is in A or T-shape, it can run effectively.
Under these conditions, the Binding Google function will automatically bind the clothing according to the binding information in the virtual model.
Click the App button in the Binding Google column to apply the Binding Google function.
To confirm whether the Binding Google function is applied, we apply a few poses.
As you can see, once the Binding Google function is completed, the crowd will be applied to the clothing,
allowing it to be switched with the virtual model during the pose change.
When you apply a different pose, you can observe the seamless switching between the clothing and the virtual model.
At this time, please note that when the Binding Google function is applied, a warning message will appear, as shown in the slide.
If you choose Yes, the clothing will be simulated.
At the same time,
the Binding Google information will be deleted.
On the contrary, if you choose No, the clothing will be simulated and the Binding Google information will be retained.
After applying the Binding Google function, a new option will appear in this column.
Next, let's take a look at how to apply these options.
When you click on the update button, the clothing will be binded to Google again according to its current state.
On the right side of the update button is the brush tool.
When you click on the brush tool, the Everywhere window will be closed for a short time,
and there will be a blood-like window related to the brush tool in the same position.
The purpose of the brush tool is to make it easy to modify.
When activating the tool, the 3D clothing will automatically switch to the white texture.
The joints become visible.
The tool can be adjusted in detail,
allowing you to set the extent to which each part of the clothing is affected by the virtual model joint movement.
You can use the brush tool to adjust each part of the clothing to reflect the joint movement of the virtual model.
Press the control key on the keyboard to make joint selection.
It is convenient to automatically confirm the weight of each joint.
The brush window is composed of two options, weight and carving.
Let's first take a look at the weight option.
In the weight option, you can use the brush tool to adjust the extent to which the online grid of clothing is binded to Google.
Here, the weight refers to the influence or increase of the online grid.
Use the brush tool.
Use the brush tool to adjust the online grid of clothing.
The brush tool can also modify the process of weight selection of certain areas on the clothing,
which is called weight selection.
After weight selection,
more smooth and natural movement can be shown,
and various poses can be switched seamlessly.
Although automatic binding of the bone grid will automatically divide the weight,
it is also very important to perform weight selection operations when adjusting joints or poses,
to ensure that clothing moves naturally along the body.
The brush tool can allow you to check or modify the clothes
or in areas that may not be correct when modifying clothing.
Or after changing joints or posture,
the clothing can follow the movement of the body.
The combination mode of the weight brush provides three options,
increase, decrease and smooth.
You can use the shortcut keys to control and tab to switch.
Increase will increase the weight, decrease will decrease the weight,
and smooth will adjust the weight value to balance the surrounding area.
In the properties of the brush, you can adjust the strength, size, hardness and depth.
The strength can be set to the strength of the brush.
You can use the slider or the shortcut keys to adjust the size.
The size can be set to the size of the brush.
The shortcut keys are the left and right middle brackets.
The hardness can be adjusted to the strength difference between the center of the brush and the edge.
Finally, the depth represents the depth of the brush.
You can reset the properties of the brush by pressing the reset button.
Pressing the reset button can release the brush tool and return to the EveryMill window.
Now let's use the weight brush described above to adjust the weight.
In the 3D window, press the Ctrl key and press the joints of the virtual model
to check the corresponding weight assigned to these joints.
The color display follows red.
The color display follows green and blue.
In this row, the red area represents the higher weight distribution,
and the blue area represents the lower weight distribution.
The weight value is zero in the area where the color is not displayed.
The more weight assigned to a specific area, the greater the influence in the animation process.
This helps to control the movement more smoothly and naturally.
In addition, you can also use the brush in the 2D version of the window to adjust the weight.
When you open the window, you can see the virtual model joints.
You can select the joints, move them or use the pre-made posture to confirm the clothes,
whether they can penetrate or follow the unnatural body area.
When you find that the area needs to be modified, you can adjust the fusion mode and brush properties,
increase or decrease the weight of the brush to match the weight of the brush.
When adjusting the weight, if you find that the specific point, the peak point,
and the weight around the weight are clearly different, you can use the weight hammer.
This function will automatically adjust the weight of the point,
making the point more similar to its adjacent position.
To use the weight hammer, you need to press the Shift key and press the desired peak point.
When you press the Shift key, the mouse light will change from brush shape to red dot,
indicating that you can identify the peak point.
For example, the bottom of the nightclothes, pants, sleeves,
and pants, these specific areas of the grid,
some parts may be affected by unnecessary joints,
and thus cause deformation.
This function is very helpful in solving problems in this area.
When adjusting the weight, if there is a situation where the selected joint point should not be affected,
or the relevant joint point affects the grid and needs to be corrected,
or you need to make complex weight adjustments in a complex model,
you can use the lock joint function.
This function can prevent certain joints from being affected.
When adjusting the weight of other joints, the locked joint will not be affected.
If you want to lock a single joint, you need to press the Alt key and press the joint,
and after setting the lock, the joint will be highlighted in red.
If you want to lock all joints, you need to press the Alt key and press the right button to identify the joint.
If you want to remove the lock on a single joint,
you need to press the Alt key and press the joint.
If you want to remove the lock on all joints,
you need to press the Alt key and press the right button to identify the joint.
The operation is the same as the previous one.
Next, let's come to the options related to carving and searching with the carving brush.
We can directly press the carving option from the middle right of the circle.
You can also use the shortcut keys to control and press the focus symbol,
and switch to carving to adjust the brush mode.
When applying the automatic binding to Google's clothing,
you can use the carving brush to raise or lower the surface of the clothing grid to modify its shape.
The carving brush has two integration modes,
and you can use the Ctrl and Tab to switch.
Next, let's start with the type of the carving brush.
When you need to pull the surface of the clothing from the inside of the virtual model,
or adjust the overlap layer,
the carving brush will be very helpful.
The carving brush will be very helpful.
When you need to adjust the area of the single area and drag the brush,
the selected area will move along.
The important point is that this operation will not affect the full weight.
Next, let's look at the flat brush type.
The flat brush is used to soften the surface of the clothing or to soften any rigid areas.
When you need to apply the single area and drag the brush,
the surface of the area will be flat and close to the surrounding.
The characteristics of the carving brush are similar to the full weight brush,
including strength, size, hardness and depth.
You can adjust these parameters according to your needs.
When changing the posture of the virtual model,
determine the area of the clothing that needs to be adjusted,
and use the functions of the full weight brush and the carving brush that we have learned so far to make the necessary adjustments.
After completing the binding structure,
press the exit button and return to the Aribel window.
After completing the binding structure, press the exit button and return to the Aribel window.
After completing the binding structure,
press the exit button and return to the Aribel window.
In the Aribel window, select the second material option.
After selecting the material option,
the interface will be automatically changed to UV editing mode.
Regarding the concept of UV,
UV refers to the process of opening the surface of the 3D model into a 2D image.
Through UV hard setting,
the texture will be applied to the surface of the 3D model in a way that is similar to the 2D display.
UV fill is a function that can automatically arrange UV coordinates of clothing without overlapping.
so that the size of the image file becomes larger.
In addition, you can also set the size of the interface,
such as the diameter between the UV panels,
increase the size of the interface, and expand the diameter between the panels.
When you click the fill UV function in the upper right corner,
the Everywell window will be turned off immediately,
and a detailed UV fill window will appear.
In the UV fill window, you can set and apply relevant options.
The fill ratio is the height and width ratio of the automatic UV,
that is, the ratio of the square area of the coordinates
and the square outer frame of the entire panel.
The default value is 95, and can be adjusted between 80 and 100.
The value close to 100 will try to arrange the UV as perfectly as possible in a square area,
but it may increase the fill time.
Use rotation to allow the UV to rotate during the fill process.
Use fixed ratio to set the ratio between UVs.
At the same time,
adjust the UV ratio between UVs.
You can also adjust the overall size of the UV picture.
0 to 1 default shows the UV area.
The selected UV is placed in the 0-0 frame.
Use the selected frame option.
You can specify the required frame to fill in the selected UV.
Click Reset to reset all options.
When you click the application,
the UV will be filled in according to the specified options.
After setting the options,
the application will start the UV fill for the entire UV picture.
If you need to fill in multiple UV pictures for different types of panels or other purposes,
you can select the required panels in the UV editor,
and then click Use to fill them in.
After completing the UV fill,
press the exit key to return to the Airwell window.
The back-up texture is a function
that can generate stickers for high-quality objects,
and then show the optimization function of the multi-layer grid.
The optimization function of the multi-layer grid
can also be used in the application.
When the application is successfully implemented,
the 3D object of the optimization function of the grid is highlighted.
By using the back-up texture function,
high-quality textures similar to high-quality models can be implemented,
but the size of the file is smaller,
which will bring more efficient work flow and resource use.
By using the back-up texture of Airwell,
we can only use the optimized low-quality model
to generate details,
and the environment light to guide the stickers,
instead of creating high-quality models alone.
Detailed hair line stickers are a kind of texture stickers,
which help to show the surface details of high-quality models in a more three-dimensional way,
without the need to increase the number of cross-sectional grid.
It does this by conveying detailed surface information,
without the need for an extra number of cross-sectional.
The environment light block sticker is used to show the gray texture texture.
By tracking the light, it highlights the shadow area on the 3D model surface.
Highlighting the darker areas indicates that less lighting is received in this area,
and the brighter areas indicate that the surface lighting is good.
The sticker increases the sense of reality by predicting the effect of indirect lighting in the simulated environment.
Choose the detailed hair line sticker and the environment light block sticker in the back window.
You can adjust the sun number set by the environment light block sticker to set the number of light lines calculated by each pixel.
The larger the number, the better the quality of the result.
However, the calculation time will increase.
Click on the application to generate a sticker.
After the application is completed, a new icon will appear on the right side of each sticker option.
First, click on Preview.
You can see the sticker that can be simulated in the 3D window.
Below each sticker, you can enter the intensity value or adjust the slider to change the details to find the intensity of the sticker.
The default value is 100.
You can set it from 0 to the maximum value of 200.
Next to the preview, there is a trash can icon that allows you to delete the sticker.
In the material list, you can copy or create a new material and apply the required material to the selected version.
Initially, the material was created according to the number of UV frames.
You can right-click on the material to rename or delete the material.
Click on the new add-on to add new materials.
You can click on copy and copy the selected material.
And by clicking on the application, the previously created material will be applied to the version.
The delete button can delete the material and only delete the unused material.
You can click on the upload button to upload your work.
The costume will be uploaded to Connect.
You can also download it from it.
Please note that if you are not satisfied with the upload conditions, it will display warning information and you will not be able to upload the file.
Successful upload must meet four conditions.
First, the virtual model, including the joints, must appear in the 3D window.
Second, all versions must be binded to Google.
Third, all UVs must be filled in.
Each UV is located in one frame.
Finally, there must be a detailed drawing of the back.
To ensure that all conditions are met, click on the upload at the bottom of the AirReveal window.
The FBX setting window will appear.
The default setting is as follows.
If you have a specific setting,
please set the option and confirm it.
After connecting to the Connect upload page,
when the 3D window on the project page is converted and completed,
you can download the FBX and download the costume FBX files.
You can also check the transformed costumes in the AirReveal in the Connect page.
In addition, you can download the ZPRJ and FBX files from the list of the project.
After all the work is done,
close the AirReveal window.
If you need to save the progress in the middle
or want to use the file for further work,
you can save it as a project file in Cloud.
It is the same as the standard file saving method.
The file is saved as a project file.
All the information applied in the AirReveal window
will be saved in the ZPRJ file.
Next, I would like to talk about the optimization of 2D functions.
First, let's talk about
the optimization of the editing link.
From this version,
it is easier to confirm the direction of the link setting.
Let's take a look at the demonstration file.
In the window of the 2D version,
use the edit version tool to press the Shift key
and select the link that needs to be linked.
On the selected line,
right-click and select the link in the menu.
Then, you can see that
the link direction on the selected multiple lines
is indicated by the arrow.
Next, press the Shift key
and select the link that needs to be linked.
The direction remains the same.
As you can see,
the empty line can be confirmed
that the lines have been set to link.
The arrow on the line
indicates the direction of the link setting that needs to be changed.
The optimization of this function
can make it easier for us to confirm the direction of the link setting,
so that we can modify the link more quickly.
Next, I would like to introduce the optimization of the format function.
From this version,
we have improved the function of copying the format information,
making it more convenient,
and even when changing the size,
we can keep the previous
and other modified format shapes as much as possible.
Next, we will take a look at the improvements
through the demonstration file.
First, we will talk about the improvements related to the code
of the button and the eye.
In the previous version,
we can only enter the value of the code
in the code table in the attribute editor
to set the code information for the button and the eye.
After the improvement,
we can directly copy and paste
the required code information
into the button and the eye.
This makes the operation easier.
Next, we will use the edit format tool
to do the operation.
Select the edit format tool,
right-click on the button
to use the button of the version in the 2D version window,
then select copy.
Right-click on the button to paste the code value button.
You can choose to paste the x or y value
or paste the x and y values at the same time.
In the attribute editor,
you can see that the code value has been pasted.
You can also paste the code value
on the eye,
as the button does.
Right-click on the button to paste the code value
of the eye that has the same code value as the button,
then select copy.
Right-click on the button to paste the code information
of the eye,
select paste.
As you can see,
the function has been improved.
You can copy and paste the code value of the eye
that has the same code value as the button.
Next is the improvement related to
the copy and paste code value.
In the past,
when copying and pasting a specific position,
such as the x or y value of the code,
the remaining values that have not been pasted
could not be kept unchanged.
This brings about the unchanged.
From the beginning of the version,
we have improved it.
Even if the copy and paste
a certain position value,
the remaining values can still be unchanged.
Select the edit format tool,
right-click on the button,
then select the copy and paste
and select the copy.
Right-click on the button,
and paste the code value.
Select the y value from the paste.
In the data editor,
check the section and the outside
of the x value.
You can see,
even if the information about x is only pasted in the x value,
the x value remains unchanged.
As you can see,
the function has been improved.
Even if you copy and paste a specific position of the code value,
you can also keep the remaining position of the value unchanged.
The third optimization about the code function is to copy and paste the code value through the lines.
In the previous version, you need to mainly copy and paste the code value,
but from the beginning of the version, we have improved it.
You can copy and paste the code value with the lines as units,
so that you can modify the code more easily.
First, select the edit code tool to operate.
Right-click to copy and paste the code value of the board line,
then select copy.
Right-click to paste the corresponding line on the board of the code value,
then select X and Y from the paste.
If you need to copy and paste other lines other than this line,
you can do this operation for each line.
You can also copy and paste the code value of the board line.
As shown in the operation,
the board can copy and paste the code value through the lines.
Next, let's look at the last important improvement of the code.
In the past, when we selected a specific core code size
and edited the board again,
we had to modify all other values again.
This will make it inconvenient.
Through this improvement,
we have optimized the user experience.
After modifying the board,
even if we switch to other numbers,
we can maintain the previous simulated form.
Let's use the edit board tool to modify the board
and take a look at the specific improvements.
Now let's change the size below the code line.
You can see that even if we change the previous S code size
to M or L,
the 3D form of the modified board remains unchanged.
Only the modified board will be able to simulate its form again.
Next, let's look at the optimization of the core code of the board.
This is an improvement related to the core code layer.
In the previous version,
when the core code layer is operated from the inside and outside of the core code layer,
the code line outside the board is a continuous whole code line.
Therefore, when you want to set the core code in a section or area,
you need to delete the core code and then edit the core code again.
From this version,
the core code is divided into separate sections
and can be edited separately.
In this version,
right-click on the board
and select the core code inside or outside the core code layer from the menu.
If you look at the core code,
you can see that each section has a separate core code.
For example,
we want to delete the core code of the core board.
In the previous version,
you need to delete the entire core code,
and then delete the parts outside the core code.
But now you only need to delete the core code.
This way,
because the core code is automatically set at the end of the line,
it is easier to adjust the core code at each end of the line,
so that it can work more effectively.
Next, let's look at the improvement related to the core code.
From this version,
you can see that the core code has been applied in the 2D board window.
Now,
you can check the difference between the core code and the actual core code
to see how much the core code has been increased or decreased.
In the 2D board window,
select all the core code.
Then,
change the core code to 95
and simulate it.
In the previous version,
after the core code has been applied,
you can only check the result in the 3D window.
In the 2D version,
in the green table at the left of the 2D board window,
select the And Input
Inbut
view.
Input
sample
The shirt panel that is 100% larger will create a pink line on the outside of the panel.
If the panel does not change the shrink rate, even if the shrink rate is turned on, the pink line will not appear.
Next, I will explain the optimization of the 3D function and the application of the symmetrical panel.
In this version, the simulation can be applied to the symmetrical panel to quickly complete the same shape left and right.
In the 3D window, select the panel that needs to be copied to the simulation form.
After selecting the panel, right-click and select the application of the symmetrical panel form.
This function can retain the existing shrink line and apply the simulation form to the symmetrical panel.
If the panel is not set to symmetrical, when selecting the application of the symmetrical panel form, a warning message will appear.
It shows that some selected panels are not set to symmetrical.
The application of the symmetrical panel form can only be applied to the 3D model.
This function can only be applied to the symmetrical panel of the 3D model.
Next, I will explain the optimization of the functional optimization of the 3D model.
Display the 3D model to try on and wear the suit.
In the previous version, it is difficult to check through the naked eye whether the 3D model is wearing the suit.
From this version, the function has been updated.
You can check by opening and closing the display of the 3D model to try on and wear the suit.
First, I applied the 3D model to try on and wear the suit before opening.
In the previous version, I applied the 3D model to try on and wear the suit.
In the 3D window, the digital menu bar shows the 3D model.
Click on the 3D model to try on and wear the suit icon.
Then you can see the 3D model to try on and wear the suit.
If you want to hide the 3D model, click on the icon to try on and wear the suit.
Next is the improvement related to materials.
First, I added the multidirectional grid optimization function.
In the previous version, I mentioned multidirectional grid optimization in the Everywhere section.
Next, let's take a closer look at this function.
In the work, if the file is too large and requires the size of a slightly optimized high-quality copy,
including the copy, the button, and the pull-head, the pull-head, and the index,
you can use the multidirectional grid optimization tool added in the corresponding attribute editor
to help you easily store and use your copy files.
In order to check whether the 3D model is wearing the suit, click on the icon to try on and wear the suit.
In order to check whether the 3D model is wearing the suit,
click on the icon to try on and wear the suit.
When you click on the corresponding button, the button, the pull-head, the pull-head, and the index,
you will see a multidirectional grid optimization tool at the bottom of the attribute editor.
Click on the download menu on the right side of the multidirectional grid optimization tool.
You can see two types.
One is the default mesh grid type.
And the other is the bare-board flat type.
Mesh grid type is a method to optimize objects by reducing the number of grid lines.
And the bare-board flat type can be optimized by shaping objects into flat images.
First, select the Mesh grid type.
At this time, a count technology will appear at the bottom.
The input value will show the number of multidirectional grid lines of the object.
If the number is changed to 5000,
you can see that the number of grid lines of the object in the 3D window is reduced.
If the number of multidirectional grid lines is too low here,
for example, lower than 800,
there will be a larger change in the final appearance and a lower quality.
On the other hand, we input 50,000.
You can see that the maximum grid number that can be applied is the grid number of the original file.
It cannot exceed the number.
In addition, it should be noted that the current multidirectional grid optimization function
can only be applied to button, copy, pull head, pull piece, and straight button.
It cannot be applied to the line.
Next, we will change the type to the bare-board flat type.
At this time, the 3D object will become a flat image.
If you want to reduce the size of the file, you can try using this option.
Next is the optimization related to the sticker.
In the new version, you can set the rotation angle of each color sticker
in order to optimize it.
And when the sticker is out of the version,
the original shape of the sticker will be displayed.
First, let's take a look at how to set the rotation angle of different colors.
In the main menu bar, find the editor Color Open,
and we will check the changes in different colors.
Then click the adjustment sticker tool in the 2D or 3D tool bar to select the sticker.
You can see that in the right mouse button editor,
under the sticker change message,
we have added the function of linking all the colors.
Here, by using the function of linking all the colors,
you can set the rotation angle of each color separately.
Select the sticker and rotate it,
then click the update button in the color window.
You can see that the sticker rotates only in color A,
and the rest of the colors remain the same.
Next, let's take a look at when the sticker is out of the version.
The original shape of the sticker is displayed.
In the previous version,
when the sticker is applied to the 2D version,
the sticker is set to be visible only in the area of the 2D version.
When the sticker position is set,
the area outside the sticker is not visible,
so it is very inconvenient to continuously move the sticker for inspection.
Now it has been improved to check the image of the sticker even outside the 2D version.
Next, go back to the 2D window,
and move the sticker to the position where it is related to the outside of the version.
You can see that the sticker is not only displayed in the 2D version,
but also visible outside.
And only by using the adjustment sticker tool,
you can select the sticker in the 2D window or 3D window,
so that it can display all,
otherwise the sticker is not visible in the part outside the version.
Through the improved function,
we can rotate the sticker and check the sticker in different colors more easily.
In addition,
we have added the option of adding and deleting all unused items.
In the new version,
the items that are not assigned and unused in the 3D window can be deleted at once.
This option can be used for all object objects in the 3D window.
For example, let's see the button in the 3D window.
You can see that there are four buttons in these buttons that have not been used,
and two of them are applied to the costume.
On the unused button,
click on the button on the right,
and select the button to delete all unused buttons from the list.
You can see that the unused items will be deleted.
This can help us to manage unused items more effectively.
Next is the update about rendering.
In the new version,
we added the option of controlling the size of the round top in the skylight attribute.
We can find the round top parameters of the skylight in the rendering light setting,
by adjusting the size of the round top light to adapt the scene.
First, open the light line attribute in the rendering window,
and open the round top size.
This makes a gap in the background when moving the camera.
When you need to direct the light pattern to the ground,
this is very useful.
The round top control is basically made up of three parts,
the bottom of the hemisphere,
the ground,
and the transition area between the two.
First is the radius parameter.
As the value increases,
the radius of the whole round top becomes wider.
The smallest value is 1 meter.
When the value is set to the smallest value,
you can see that the radius of the light also becomes narrower.
At this time,
you can see that the upper end of the virtual model and the costume are not lighted.
Here the default value is 4 meters.
Next is the ground projection height.
If you increase the value,
you will see that the image of the ground surface at the bottom
will rise to the top of the hemisphere.
Accordingly,
the projection value of the light will also change.
Therefore,
you can see that the light reflected on the virtual model will also change.
Here the default value is 1 meter.
Finally,
it is the ground mixing option.
If you increase the value,
you will see that the ground surface at the bottom
and the hemisphere top will be roundly mixed together,
and the shape of the transition area will change.
Here the default value is 0.5.
If you want to save the original size of the change,
you can save all the optical properties as vrp files,
or click on the file storage in the top left-hand column
to save all the rendering properties as zvrp files.
Next is about the update and improvement of the animation.
In the new version,
it is more convenient to edit the animation frame and the selection in the animation.
First,
in the new version,
it is more convenient to adjust the frame rate in the animation.
When we stop the mouse at the end of the slide at the bottom,
it will display in the blue color.
Drag the slide can manually control the frame rate of the animation slide.
You can also enlarge the specific frame rate you want in the timeline
to edit the key frame.
If you want to display the entire animation frame in the timeline,
you can double-click the slide bar at the bottom,
or click the button on the far right of the bottom to adjust the animation frame range.
The smallest and largest frames displayed on the timeline and the change area
will be set to the same number of frames for the entire animation frame,
so that you can check all the frames at once.
In addition, when you export the costume file with the animation as an elembic file,
you can use the current frame option to only export a single frame.
First,
on the timeline,
place the playhead to the frame you want to extract,
or enter the corresponding value directly in the current frame.
Then,
in the main menu,
find the file,
export,
elembic og awa.
In the export elembic window,
select the animation menu,
and select the current frame option.
In this way,
only one frame will be exported,
and all other animation data will be deleted.